Bow to No One
Mary Queen of Scots is a drama, history film directed by Josie Rourke.
In 1561, Mary Stuart, widow of the King of France, returns to Scotland, reclaims her rightful throne and menaces the
future of Queen Elizabeth I as ruler of England, because she has a legitimate claim to the English throne.
Betrayals, rebellions, conspiracies and their own
life choices imperil both Queens.
They experience the bitter cost of power, until
their tragic fate is finally fulfilled.
Mary Stuart, played by Saoirse Ronan.
Queen Elizabeth I, played by Margot Robbie.
Lord Darnley, played by Jack Lowden.
John Knox, played by David Tennant.
William Cecil, played by Guy Pearce.
Bess of Hardwick, played by Gemma Chan.
Mary Queen of Scots is a 2018 historical drama film directed by Josie Rourke (in her feature directorial debut) and with a
screenplay by Beau Willimon based on John Guy's 2004 biography Queen of Scots: The True Life of Mary Stuart.
The film stars Saoirse Ronan as Mary, Queen of Scots, and Margot Robbie
as her cousin, the English monarch, Queen Elizabeth I.
Jack Lowden, Joe Alwyn, David Tennant, and Guy
Pearce also star in supporting roles.
Mary Queen of Scots had its world premiere on closing night of AFI Fest on 15 November 2018, was released
in the United States on 7 December 2018, and in the United Kingdom on 18 January 2019.
The film received mixed reviews, with praise for the performances (particularly Robbie) and
costumes, but was criticised for the screenplay and several historical inaccuracies.
The film received three nominations at the 72nd British Academy Film Awards, and two nominations,
for Best Costume Design and Best Makeup and Hairstyling, at the 91st Academy Awards.
For her performance, Robbie earned nominations for a SAG Award
and BAFTA Award for Best Supporting Actress.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
scotland, cousin, royal family, biography.
The tone is emotional.